<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://digitalrift.co/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="http://digitalrift.co/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><updated>2018-05-21T15:52:52+00:00</updated><id>http://digitalrift.co/</id><title type="html">Digital Rift</title><subtitle>Digital Rift is a collective of passionate, experienced esports designers and developers. We're a team of gamers who live to build awesome digital experiences in esports.</subtitle><author><name>Digital Rift</name></author><entry><title type="html">Misfits Website</title><link href="http://digitalrift.co/projects/2018/esports/misfits-gaming" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Misfits Website"/><published>2018-03-16T17:56:12+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-16T17:56:12+00:00</updated><id>http://digitalrift.co/projects/2018/esports/misfits_gaming</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://digitalrift.co/projects/2018/esports/misfits-gaming">&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-brief&quot;&gt;The Brief&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p&gt;Misfits Gaming are a professional esports organisation operating out of the UK. With top tier teams across League of Legends, Overwatch and Smash Bros. they needed a website that showed the same level of quality that their players brought to the stage.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;After looking for a digital partner, us lovely folks at Rift won a competitive pitch to take charge of redesigning and rebuilding the Misfits website from the ground up. We started by speaking with Misfit’s founder and CEO Ben Spoont to identify the key factors for both their internal targets and their fans needs.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h4 id=&quot;our-process&quot;&gt;Our Process&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p&gt;After discussing their requirements we began wireframing the website structure, putting emphasis on large imagery that their creative team had been accumulating with incredible quality over the years. The website acts as a digital hub for Misfits content, linking to a range of their external digital platforms including their ecommerce store, Overwatch content pages, published YouTube videos and Twitch streams, allowing for their fans to digest all their premium content from a central place.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/05/misfits-wireframe.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Misfits Homepage Wireframe&quot; title=&quot;Homepage Wireframe&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Built on top of the WordPress platform the Misfits Gaming content team have the power to create and manage content without any delays, publishing content to their huge network of fans as soon as it happens. With this power they can take control of their roster to ensure it’s bang up-to-date, publish their upcoming matches to keep their fans engaged and hungry for wins, and have everything optimised not only for mobile devices, but for search engines as well, without even a second thought.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/05/misfits-header.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Misfits Homepage&quot; title=&quot;Homepage&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/05/misfits-article.png&quot; alt=&quot;Misfits Article Page&quot; title=&quot;Article Page&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/05/misfits-teampage.png&quot; alt=&quot;Misfits Team Roster Page&quot; title=&quot;Misfits Team Page&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h4 id=&quot;observed-results&quot;&gt;Observed Results&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p&gt;Since releasing the website 3 months ago we’ve seen traffic steadily increasing, with fans engaging with content across a range of devices and an increased number of visitors arriving from organic search as opposed to just their existing social channels.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It was an absolute pleasure working with Misfits Gaming and Ben through-out the entire project and we’ll be cheering for them as they continue to dominate the scene.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Digital Rift</name></author><summary type="html">The Brief</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://digitalrift.co/%7B%22meta%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/03/misfits-social.jpg%22,%20%22header%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/03/misfits-header_1.jpg%22,%20%22thumbnail%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/03/misfits-thumbnail.jpg%22%7D"/></entry><entry><title type="html">MnM Website</title><link href="http://digitalrift.co/projects/2018/esports/mnm-gaming" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MnM Website"/><published>2018-02-15T12:51:43+00:00</published><updated>2018-02-15T12:51:43+00:00</updated><id>http://digitalrift.co/projects/2018/esports/mnm_gaming</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://digitalrift.co/projects/2018/esports/mnm-gaming">&lt;h4 id=&quot;not-just-a-great-logo&quot;&gt;Not just a great logo&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p&gt;Working with MnM Gaming we were tasked with revamping their website to improve user experience and to better accommodate and promote rich media that they internally produce and publish.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Molotovs and Marshmallow Gaming, aside from having a fantastic name, have always strived to be more than just a fly-by-night esports team, to be sustainable and to be the standard for which UK esports teams are measured.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/05/mnm-logo-small.png&quot; alt=&quot;MnM Logo&quot; title=&quot;MnM Logo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h4 id=&quot;fortheflame&quot;&gt;#ForTheFlame&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p&gt;Already having a strong name and standing in UK esports cultivated over the last 3 years MnM their existing digital platform wasn’t doing them justice, and that’s where we came in.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We first focussed on identifying their existing user journeys; boiling this down to accommodating both the teams loyal fans looking for content and information, and also prospective sponsors looking for accomplishments and history. By isolating these 2 journeys we were able to create an equally rewarding experience for both of these personas and since release we’ve seen a consistent increase in user visits, both locally and internationally, and a reduction on bounce-rate.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h4 id=&quot;getting-graphic&quot;&gt;Getting graphic&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p&gt;Using the large media library being continually updated by the MnM organisation we were able to utilise large header imagery and add more structure to page content, streamlining the users experience and making the process more interactive.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/05/about-mnm-players.png&quot; alt=&quot;MnM Website Preview&quot; title=&quot;MnM Website Preview&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Around team pages we aimed to provide each team’s page with a unique and interactive experience that introduces not only the team, but also the game and it’s mechanics. The assumption that a visitor already has in-depth knowledge of what an ADC is in League of Legends, or how tank meta works in Overwatch, just isn’t accurate and we focussed on accommodating both your newbie and pro alike, giving them both a great experience.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h4 id=&quot;putting-the-pieces-together&quot;&gt;Putting the pieces together&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p&gt;We put together wireframes for a number of the site pages and working with Kalvin Chung, who turned his hand to website design for this project, we collaboratively put together a unique design that checks all of MnM Gaming’s boxes. We then brought these designs to life on top of the WordPress platform, allowing them to manage everything they could need to.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We’re extremely proud of the MnM website so be sure to pay them a visit and cheer them on.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot; hide_thread=&quot;true&quot; data-conversation=&quot;none&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;And it's got mobile support making the site so easy to navigate love the simplicity sometimes less is more &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/KalKalCS?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@KalKalCS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Thomas Campbell_(@TPO_TwoRounds) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/TPO_TwoRounds/status/954068133731602432?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;January 18, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;_ &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Digital Rift</name></author><summary type="html">Not just a great logo</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://digitalrift.co/%7B%22meta%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/02/mnm-social.jpg%22,%20%22header%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/02/mnm-header.jpg%22,%20%22thumbnail%22=%3E%22/uploads/2018/02/mnm-thumbnail.jpg%22%7D"/></entry><entry><title type="html">OpTic Website</title><link href="http://digitalrift.co/projects/2016/esports/optic-gaming" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="OpTic Website"/><published>2016-04-20T12:46:47+00:00</published><updated>2016-04-20T12:46:47+00:00</updated><id>http://digitalrift.co/projects/2016/esports/optic_gaming</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://digitalrift.co/projects/2016/esports/optic-gaming">&lt;h4 id=&quot;content-is-king&quot;&gt;Content is king&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p&gt;Since the birth of OpTic Gaming in 2006, the organisation and its members have used video as a tool to establish themselves as an esports powerhouse. My idea encapsulated this and took their multimedia needs into consideration.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2016/04/optic-img-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;OpTic Gaming News&quot; title=&quot;Homepage Feed&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h4 id=&quot;dynamic-content-delivery&quot;&gt;Dynamic Content Delivery&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p&gt;OpTic needs to deliver valuable content to it’s audience. However, sheer popularity is not enough to be the go to platform at this scale. To establish OpTic Gaming as the source of news that users keep on returning to it’s important to communicate content in a clear and consistent manor that puts the users needs first&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Users shouldn’t have to spend any additional time searching the site for what they came for. OpTic Gaming will have many visitors that come and browse, but this alone is not enough to &lt;strong&gt;maximise the potential of the site and generate page views that turn the site the site into additional value for sponsors&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2016/04/optic-img-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;OpTic Gaming Matches&quot; title=&quot;Match Feed&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h4 id=&quot;elevating-the-brand&quot;&gt;Elevating the brand&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p&gt;The OpTic brand is more than the logo. It is the people. Whilst many organisations strive to promote their own social media over it’s players, OpTic Gaming proudly places it’s members in the limelight.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Honouring this value I made team pages a testament to the individual success of each player. Visitors to the site should understand how important each player, manager, and entertainer is. This is why I decided to reinvent the conventional team page found on many esports sites.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2016/04/optic-img-3.png&quot; alt=&quot;OpTic Gaming Team&quot; title=&quot;Team Player Profile&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Updated May 2018: You can find the site we designed for OpTic gaming at&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://optic.tv/&quot; title=&quot;OpTic Website&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;optic.tv&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Their developers have since altered and removed portions of our design.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Digital Rift</name></author><summary type="html">Content is king</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://digitalrift.co/%7B%22meta%22=%3E%22%22,%20%22header%22=%3E%22/uploads/2016/04/optic-header.jpg%22,%20%22thumbnail%22=%3E%22/uploads/2016/04/optic-thumbnail.jpg%22%7D"/></entry></feed>